人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  惠子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  卫老哥
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  4女之后
译  幸田实果子
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹  阿包  兜兜爹
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第六集
你想我了吗
Did you miss me?
我们在一起会很好玩的
We're gonna have so much fun together.
监控组织
音频拦截
破译数据流
他在四处调查
He is digging around,
就快查到了
getting way too close.
要灭他的口吗
Should we silence him?
不能让他毁了我们的行动
We can't let him jeopardize our operation.
投票决定吧
Put it to a vote.
监控组织
破译网络
统计投票
暴力威胁迫近
联系系统管理员
我进来了  芬奇  能告诉我这是哪里吗
I'm in, Finch. Care to tell me where?
你进入的公寓是肖女士的
The apartment you're in belongs to Ms. Shaw.
我保证过要尊重彼此的界线
I promised to respect her boundaries,
但整整八个小时
but for eight hours,
我们商定好的联系方式毫无反应
our agreed-upon means of contact have gone unanswered.
所以你就追踪她了
So you tracked her down.
肖女士虽行为暴力  不擅交流
Ms. Shaw may be violent and uncommunicative,
但从不拖沓
but she is never tardy.
肯定是有事发生  我需要你查清楚
Something is amiss, and I need you to find out what.
你在忙什么
So what are you up to?
练腰
My waist approximately.
别太娇气了  哈罗德
Don't be so delicate, Harold.
我需要你进来细查
I need you to get in there and dig.
看  人啊  会把名片放在脏衣服中
See, people, they put business cards in dirty clothes,
号码记在纸巾上
jot phone numbers on napkins.
只要找到一个亲戚的名字就够了
A single relative's name is all we need.
小心老鼠
Watch out for rats.
老鼠
Rats?
你大概也猜到了
As you may have guessed,
我们有了新号码  蒂姆西・斯隆
we have a new number: Timothy Sloan,
纽约公定遗产管理的遗产调查员
an estate investigator for the New York Public Administrator.
如果有人去世  又没有亲属
If somebody dies without an apparent next of kin
比如某位生前住在这里的囤积狂
like the compulsive hoarder who used to live here,
他们就派斯隆来找
they send in Sloan to find one.
那有人去世
So when somebody dies,
斯隆查出谁应该获得遗产
Sloan figures out who gets their stuff.
正是
Exactly.
我扮成了他的新搭档
I'm undercover as his new partner.
芬奇  你知道我不喜欢你没我陪伴  孤身犯险
Finch, you know I don't like you heading into danger without me.
我也不喜欢现在这样
I'm not so thrilled about my current circumstances either,
但我需要你在那里
but I need you where you are.
说到这个  你有发现吗
Speaking of which, have you found anything?
没什么出奇的
Nothing unexpected.
《恋人无情》
[推理小说家]雷蒙德・钱德勒
Raymond Chandler.
我从小就爱读
I grew up reading this stuff.
一直梦想着当名侦探
I always dreamed about becoming a detective.
你试过读警察学校吗
Did you try the police academy?
人家不太待见
Turns out they're not crazy about
枪都射不准的人
hiring someone who can't shoot straight.
查过冰箱了吗
You check the fridge yet?
去那里查亲属
For a next of kin?
发霉的剩菜背后没准儿有惊喜啊
You'd be surprised what pops up behind moldy leftovers.
没什么  只有过期的牛奶
Nothing in here but old milk,
貌似曾是意大利面的一大团
an enormous quantity of something that used to be pasta,
等等
and-- wait.
我说什么来着
What'd I tell you?
冷藏的温度能保护胶卷不褪色
The cooler temperatures keep the film from fading.
中奖了  自己看
Jackpot. See for yourself.
生日快乐
双胞胎姐妹
玛西亚&安妮
囤积狂玛西亚有个妹妹
Marcia the Hoarder has a sister.
就是说有继承人了
Which means we have an heir.
干得好  哈罗德  这边工作搞定
Good work, Harold. Our job here is done.
里瑟先生  我现在得离开了
Mr. Reese, I have to leave now.
找到我们需要的了
We found what we needed.
不幸的是  我也找到了
Unfortunately, so did I.
电击枪屑
Taser confetti,
使用后就会爆出
ejected whenever one is fired.
我想应该不可能是她电击自己吧
I suppose it's too much to hope she tased herself.
就凭肖  有可能
Knowing Shaw, it's possible.
但要我猜  我看她是有麻烦了
But if I had to guess, I'd say she's in trouble.
抱歉啦
Sorry about that.
抱歉啥  电击  下药
Which part: the tasing, the drugging,
还是现在这玩意儿
or whatever this is?
我得确保你乖乖听我说话
I had to make sure you'd hear me out.
她需要我们的帮助
She needs our help,
我猜你不会乐意自愿帮忙
and I figured you wouldn't come willingly.
她
She?
机器给了我一个任务
The machine's given me a mission,
第一步  跟你组队
And step one is to team up with you.
免了
I'll pass.
信任问题
Trust issues.
再说  机器已经派了任务给哈罗德和政府方
Besides, the machine gives missions to Harold and the government--
相关的  无关的
relevant, irrelevant.
它为什么还要跟你说
Why would it be talking to you?
因为现在  出现了第三方
Because now, there's a third category.
形势在演变
Things are evolving.
而我跟机器之间的关系略有
And my relationship with the machine is a little...
不同
different.
至于信任问题
As for trust issues,
我很乐意先迈出第一步
I'm happy to take the first step.
贮物箱里有一把枪给你
There's a gun for you in the glove compartment.
谢了  不过刀就够了
Thanks, but a knife will do just fine.
现在就给我个理由解释下
This is the part where you give me one good reason
凭什么要我相信你的话
why I should believe anything you say.
1988年10月2日
October 2, 1988.
你父亲开车带你
You took a road trip with your father
去看休斯顿油人队和费城老鹰队的[橄榄球]比赛
to watch the Houston Oilers play the Philadelphia Eagles.
-他给你买了件运动衫  -不许提我父亲
- He bought you a sweatshirt... - Don't talk about my father.
它告诉你的
It told you that?
机器信任我
The machine trusts me,
虽然你不信任我
even if you don't.
你为机器工作了数年
You spent years working for the machine,
她从不出错
and she was never wrong.
如果你不帮我
If you don't help me,
有人会毁了她
someone might destroy her,
无辜百姓会因此丧命
and innocent people will die.
忘掉你对我的感觉
Forget how you feel about me.
你对那会有何感觉
How would you feel about that?
好
Okay.
我会先忘掉对你的感觉
I'll forget how I feel about you.
不过等这一切结束
But when this is over,
你就祈祷我别想起来吧
you better hope I don't remember.
晚上好  里瑟先生
Good evening, Mr. Reese.
没惹麻烦吧  芬奇
Staying out of trouble, Finch?
暂时是  但恐怕那位斯隆先生并非如此
For the moment, although I'm not sure our Mr. Sloan could say the same.
我黑进了他的办公室网络查看他在干什么
I hacked into his office network to see what he's up to.
似乎这位遗产调查员
It appears our estate investigator
对一件不归他管的案子有不寻常的兴趣
has taken an unorthodox interest in a case that isn't his.
杰森・格林菲尔德  两周前因吸毒过量死亡
Jason Greenfield, died two weeks ago of an apparent heroin overdose,
没有亲属
no next of kin.
斯隆的兴趣怎么不寻常了
How is Sloan's interest unorthodox?
深更半夜独自摸进
Would going to a dead man's apartment alone
死人的公寓够不寻常了吧
in the middle of the night qualify?
有肖女士的线索了吗
Any progress in finding Ms. Shaw?
她那栋楼没有摄像头
Her building doesn't have cameras,
不过街对面的楼有
but the one across the street does.
他们同意你看监控录像带了吗
And they agreed to let you see the footage?
说服了一下  外加十字锁喉
After some convincing and a sleeper hold.
关键是我查出了是谁劫走了肖
Point is I found out who took Shaw,
你肯定不会喜欢
and you're not gonna like it.
找到她们  里瑟先生  要快
Find them, Mr. Reese. Now.
你为什么要跟踪我
Why the hell are you following me?
此狗非比寻常  会叫更会咬  相信我
Contrary to the saying, his bite is far worse. Trust me.
小熊  [荷兰语]安静
Bear, stil.
也许你该解释下你为什么要闯进
Now, perhaps you'd like to explain why you're breaking
杰森・格林菲尔德的公寓
into Jason Greenfield's apartment
偷走他的财产  包括那块表
and taking his possessions, including that watch.
我不是贼
I'm not a thief.
看背面
Read the back.
送给杰森・格林菲尔德  斯隆家赠
"To Jason Greenfield from the Sloan family."
你认识他
You knew him?
杰森是我的领养兄弟
Jason was my foster brother.
我来这里是想查出是谁谋杀了他
I'm here 'cause I'm trying to solve his murder.
这是我和杰森
It's me and Jason.
他的亲生父母是瘾君子
His parents were addicts.
他十四岁时  他们在家制冰毒把房子烧了
They burnt the house down cooking meth when he was 14.
我爸妈一直想领养小孩  所以
My mom and dad had started fostering, so...
就成了兄弟
instant brother.
他十八岁时  我父母把这送给了他
When he was 18, my parents gave him this,
就是  想让他记得
you know, just-- just to remind him
无论如何  他都有我们
that no matter what, he always had us.
我真希望他相信
I just wish he believed it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
杰森一直在当什么黑客
Jason always messed around with hacking.
搬出来之后  他就更痴迷了
And after moving out, he got more obsessed,
和其他黑客混在一起的时间越来越多
and spent more and more time with other hackers.
最后  不见影儿了
Finally just fell off the map.
两周前  我在查看其他调查员的案件时
Two weeks ago, I'm looking at another investigator's case files,
发现了他的名字
and I see his name.
我不能相信
I couldn't believe it.
他发过誓他永远不会碰毒品
I mean, he swore that he would never start using.
现在却死于吸毒过量
Now, he dies of an O.D.?
-人会变  -杰森不会
- People do change. - Not Jason.
这点绝对不会
Not--not-- not about that.
我一走进来  就知道了
The minute I walked in, I knew.
我去过很多死掉的瘾君子家里
I mean, I've been to the homes of a lot of heroin addicts who died.
知道什么东西你看不到吗
You know what you don't see?
高档电视
High-end TV.
立体音响
Stereo.
金表
Gold watch?
全都会被卖掉换毒品
It all goes to getting their fix.
你认为有人杀了他  然后掩盖了罪行
You think someone killed him, then covered it up.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I'm not sure.
但是看看这屋里缺了什么
But let's take a look at what isn't here.
没电脑  没平板  没手机
No computer, no tablet, no phone.
什么样的黑客会没有电脑
What kind of hacker doesn't have a computer?
的确奇怪
It does seem strange.
你没找到任何存储数据的东西吗
You found nothing with any data in it whatsoever?
你进来前  我在微波炉里发现一个优盘
I found a flash drive in the microwave before you came in.
看起来他毁过了
Looks like he fried it.
可以吗
May I?
我想尽量帮忙
I'd like to help if I can.
杰森也许毁过了优盘里的数据
Jason may have tried to destroy the contents of the drive.
是的  基本毁干净了
Yes, it's largely been wiped clean.
等等
Wait.
有一个数据的碎片
There's a fragment of stray data.
是封电邮的碎片
It's a piece of an email.
说了什么
What does it say?
只能修复几个词
I can only recover a few words.
"你不明白
"You don't understand.
如果我退出  他们会杀了我"
If I try to leave, they'll kill me."
问题是  他们是谁
The question is, who are they?
这又是什么
And what is this?
我在杰森的外套里找到的
I found it in Jason's jacket.
这是个地址
It's an address for...
存储仓库
a storage unit.
奇怪
That is weird.
我们的人查过  他没有存储仓库
Our guys checked. He didn't have a storage unit.
转告我们的朋友  很抱歉交钱晚了
被复制的手机
拉斯基
麦克风活动中
好  没问题
Yeah, sure.
谢了  孩子  回见
鸡
蛋
倒是个降胆固醇的法子
That's one way to lower your cholesterol.
鸡蛋盒  鸡蛋含高胆固醇
HR的保护费  给黑警的黑钱
HR's protection payment. Dirty money for dirty cops.
如常递送
Deliver it as usual.
然后查明去向
Then find out where it goes from there.
我不能
I can't do that.
你真想要惹我试试吗
Do you really wanna test me?
我手里可是有一把崭新的1911自动手枪
'Cause I've got a shiny new 1911 to back me up on that.
莫洛佐夫刚才跟你说了些什么
What did Morozov say to you back there?
问倒我了  我可不懂俄语
Beats me. I don't speak Russian.
有意思了
That's funny.
看起来你可是每个字都听懂了
'Cause it looked like you understood every word.
听着
Look.
莫洛佐夫的食品店从我小时候就在开了
Morozov's been running that deli since I was a kid.
HR知道  也很尊重
HR knows that and respects it.
这些钱只是为了表忠心
These payments are about loyalty.
我跟你说吧  拉斯基
Let me tell you something, Laskey.
用不了多久  你就会发现
One day soon, you're gonna find out
HR要你如何回报那份"忠心"了
exactly what HR expects from you in return for that loyalty.
-看清她了吗  -她就凭空出现了
- You get a good look at her? - She came outta nowhere.
收到你的消息了  莱奈尔
Got your message, Lionel.
看起来你找到了根的汽车
Looks like you found Root's car.
对  附带个疯狂故事
Yeah, and a crazy story to go with it.
那位说自己的救护车
Guy over there says this medical supply van
被开着那辆车的两个女人抢了
was just stolen by two women driving that car.
一个招手停车  说引擎故障
One waves them down, engine trouble.
他下车查看的时候
When he goes to take a look,
另一个用什么武术把他打晕了
the other one knocks him out with some kind of martial arts.
我讨厌这么说  但是根和肖
I hate to tell you, but Root and Shaw,
那俩货组队了  逆天啊
they're working as a team, a scary one.
说声谢谢不会死的
A thank-you would be nice.
芬奇  我快找到根和肖了
Finch, I'm closer to Root and Shaw.
据我所见  与其说是绑架
From what I'm seeing, it looks less like an abduction
不如说是搭档合作
and more like a partnership.
搭档合作  目的何在呢
A partnership? To what end?
不知道  但有根在  一切皆有可能
No idea, but with Root involved, anything's possible.
令人忧心的消息啊  里瑟先生
A troubling development, Mr. Reese,
我这儿还有一个
and I'm afraid I have another one.
看起来斯隆先生的领养兄弟杰森
It seems that Mr. Sloan's foster brother Jason
是被某个神秘组织谋杀的
may have been murdered by some mysterious group.
你认为威胁斯隆的是同一个组织吗
You think that same group might be the threat against Sloan?
确定的唯一办法就是搞清楚
The only way to know for sure would be to determine
谁杀害了杰森  以及为什么
who killed Jason and why.
你确定不需要我帮忙吗
Are you sure you don't need my help on this?
不  里瑟先生  追踪肖女士才是你的首要任务
No, Mr. Reese, tracking Ms. Shaw is your top priority.
好吧
All right.
但是芬奇  你需要时  我在
But, Finch, I'm here if you need me.
我刚刚打了电话
So I just got off the phone
给存储仓库中心的经理
with the manager from the storage center.
117号仓库出租给了一位约翰・格勒弗
Unit 117 was rented out to a guy named John Glover.
他根据描述想起了杰森
Now, he recognized Jason's description,
说有杰森跟一群人
said that Jason was one of a bunch of people
经常去那个仓库
who used to visit that unit at all hours.
杰森死后第二天
The day after Jason died,
同一批人过来  把那里清了个干净
those same people came back in, cleaned the place out,
用漂白剂从上到下刷了个遍
scrubbed it from top to bottom with bleach.
他们的登记资料里有约翰・格勒弗的照片吗
Did they have a photo I.D. on file for John Glover?
没有
No.
格勒弗用现金预付了一年租金
Glover paid a full year in advance with cash.
-根据我们掌握的情况  -格勒弗可能并不存在
- For all we know-- - Glover may not even exist.
看看还有没有别的仓库
Let's see if any other storage units
是用这个名字租下来的
have been rented using that name.
约翰・格勒弗名下没有了
No other rentals under John Glover,
但是在布鲁克林
but there in Brooklyn,
另有一间仓库用现金预付了一年
another unit paid for a full year in cash
租期就在他们清理约翰・格勒弗仓库的那天
and rented the same day they cleared out John Glover's unit.
这间是谁租的
Who rented that one?
萨缪尔・迈尔斯
Samuel Miles.
等等
Wait.
约翰・格勒弗  萨缪尔・迈尔斯
John Glover? Samuel Miles?
这就是联系  格勒弗和迈尔斯
That's the connection-- Glover and Miles
都是美国革命[独立战争]时期的将军
are both generals in the American Revolution.
不太可能是巧合
Hardly seems like a coincidence.
我们去找那间仓库吧
Let's go find that storage unit.
我们这个任务  到底是什么
So this mission we're on, what is it?
我们很快就会知道了
We'll find out soon enough.
你下次看到这座雕塑的时候
When you see this statue again,
想着"撞击"
think impact.
机器跟你说的吗
The machine told you that?
我倒是可以胡编
I suppose I could be making it up.
我倒是可以踹你两脚
And I suppose I could be kicking your ass.
保险
Insurance.
我们现在去哪儿
And where are we headed to now?
下面
Down.
意大利面加氧气筒可以做成热喷枪
Spaghetti and an oxygen tank make a mean thermal lance.
我要切什么
What am I cutting?
这个
This.
上次我用喷枪
You know the last time I used a blowtorch
是从不识趣儿的人嘴里撬情报
was to get intel from an uncooperative source.
告诉我来这儿是要做什么
Now, you either tell me what we're here to do,
否则我走人
or I walk.
听实话吗
Honestly?
大多数时候
Most of the time,
我都是在最后一秒才被告知要做什么
I'm told what to do a second before I have to do it.
掌握大局的  是她
The big picture, that's hers.
我唯一能确定就是
The only thing I know for sure is
我  需  要  你
I need you.
那就别挡我路
Then you should get out of my way.
等等
Wait.
安全第一
Safety first.
工作中学到的东西挺有意思
Funny, the stuff you learn from work.
我车里有铁橇  开锁器和锤子
My truck's stuffed with crowbars, key cutters, and bump hammers.
难说工作时会用到什么工具
Never know what you're gonna need for the job.
看看杀害我弟弟的凶手在这儿干什么
Let's see what the people who killed my brother were doing here.
好了  这里也空了
Good. This is empty too.
为什么预付了一整年的仓库
Why pay for a storage unit a year in advance
却一物不放
and put nothing in it?
看灰尘
Look at the dust.
这面墙可是不一样
A lot of activity along this wall here.
他们在这儿存了东西
They are storing something here.
我们只需要点不同光谱
We just need to shine a light of a different spectrum,
就是你们这行用来检测液体的
the kind somebody like you might use to detect fluids.
你有这类工具吗
You have anything like that in your truck?
有
I do.
好了  这么说你不知道我们在做什么
Okay, so you don't know what we're doing.
能至少告诉我接下来要做什么吗
Can you at least tell me what we're doing next?
非法入侵
Breaking and entering.
大门紧锁
Locked door.
手机
Phone.
少了什么
What's missing?
在你后面
Behind you.
训练有素  穿廉价西装的特工
Highly trained operative in a bad suit.
这是中情局的交接点
This is a CIA pickup site.
-特工号码  -947-0038A
- Agent number? - 947-0038 alpha.
-确认信息  -D241
- Confirmation? - Diego 241.
明天交接  上午八点
Pickup tomorrow, 0800.
把包裹准备好
Have the package ready.
好吧  什么包裹
Okay, so what's the package?
我
I am.
就这个  紫外线灯
Here you go. UV lamp.
关灯
Kill the lights.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
这是什么
What is this?
信息中心
A message center
供人秘密交流
for people who'd want to communicate without being overheard.
问题是
Question is...
这些是什么意思
what are they saying?
奇怪  看消防喷头管道
All right, that's weird. Look at this sprinkler.
它们连接的管道
It's--they're not attached to the same pipes
与其他仓库不同
that service the other units.
那里
Right there.
看起来像个电动机
Looks like some kind of motor.
摄像头  天啊  我们得
Camera. Oh, dear. We've gotta get--
我们被锁起来了
We're locked in!
是汽油
It's gasoline!
这里要被烧掉  连我们一起烧了
They're gonna burn the place down with us in it.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
我发现了是谁要活烧了我们
I believe I know who tried to burn us alive.
上次我看到这种代码
The last time I saw code like this,
是这个人在使用
it was used by this man.
彼得・科利尔
Peter Collier.
他是一个组织的成员  该组织反对
He's a member of a group trying to send a message
政府监控和侵犯隐私
about government surveillance and privacy.
他为达目的不惜杀人
And he'll kill anyone who gets in his way.
目前  科利尔是我们最确定的组织成员
So far, Collier's the most visible member of the group,
而你的领养兄弟杰森・格林菲尔德
and your foster brother Jason Greenfield
应该也是其中一员
was likely a member as well.
但杰森绝不会伤害别人
But Jason would never hurt anyone.
那应该不是他在组织里的职责
That may not have been his role in the group.
杰森优盘里的电邮
The email I recovered from Jason's flash drive
包含的字符串标识码
contained an identifier string
我在黑暗网络的一段对话中找到了匹配
that I was able to match to a conversation on the Darknet,
这是黑客间的交流
an exchange between hackers,
其中有一位备受推崇
One of whom was being lauded for
战果极其辉煌
exploits that were nothing short of astonishing.
这黑客代号"阿特拉斯7"
The hacker goes by the name of Atlas7,
希腊神话中被罚以肩擎天的泰坦神族成员  喻"身负重担"之人
但他的真实身份很清楚了
but their real identity seems clear.
-我弟弟  -正是
- My brother. - Indeed.
他的攻击对象有政府
The targets he chose are all government,
军方  数据公司
military, data-collecting corporations.
也许科利尔正是因此而注意到他
Perhaps that's what put him on Collier's radar.
他们就组队合作了
So they teamed up,
有一天  格林菲尔德想退出
and at some point, Greenfield tried to get out.
他们就要杀他
And they killed him.
他们接下来可能要对付你了
They may be coming after you now.
-我  -他们非常看重隐私
- Me? - These people value privacy.
隐蔽是最重要的  斯隆先生
Secrecy above all else, Mr. Sloan.
-发现了他们  -就捅了马蜂窝
- By uncovering them-- - You kicked the hornet's nest.
从科利尔手里保护你的最好方法
The best way to protect you from Collier
是找出他们到底在做什么
is to find out what he's up to
然后先发制人
and get out ahead of it.
存储仓库的信息
The messages in the storage units
看来是用了运动密钥加密法
appear to have been encrypted with a running key cipher.
知道密钥  就能解开代码
We find the key, we break the code.
-那密钥是什么  -一串文本
- So what's the key? - A long string of text.
一封信  一本书
A letter, a book.
杰森绝对有密钥
Jason would've had that key too.
那肯定在他公寓里
So it must be in his apartment.
我去看看
I'll go check it out.
我换个地方再深入调查
And I'll go somewhere where I can do more in-depth research.
我和你一起去
I'm coming with you.
你该留在这儿
You should stay here.
你要找解开代码的密钥  对吗
You're looking for the key to this code, right?
有件事是我最擅长的
There's something I do better than anybody else,
就是找到别人藏起来的东西
and that's finding things that people keep hidden.
拜托
Please.
让我为杰森做点事
Let me do it for Jason.
走吧
Come on.
中情局来交接了
CIA is here to pick us up.
有遗言吗
Any last words?
24381.
随便吧
Whatever.
识别码
PIN?
24381.
很高兴见到你  迪尔伯恩探员
Good to meet you, Agent Dearborn.
搜过身了吗
She been sanitized?
看来你抓的这位挺有趣
Looks like you got a fun one.
绝对超乎想象
You don't know the half of it.
拉斯基  我是西蒙斯
Laskey, it's Simmons.
去看看你朋友莫洛佐夫  我想他需要你的帮助
Go see your pal Morozov. I think he needs your help.
你是谁  莫洛佐夫呢
Who are you? Where's Morozov?
我叫你来就是为了谈这个
Exactly what I called you here to talk about.
你从莫洛佐夫那儿拿到钱后都不数了吗
When's the last time you counted the money you got from Morozov?
你觉得他藏私了
You think he's been skimming?
老大  我很了解莫洛佐夫
Boss, I've known Morozov my entire life.
-他很看重HR  -拉斯基
- He values HR. - Laskey.
你是菜鸟
You're a rookie,
所以这次我放过你  教育下就行了
so I'm gonna let you off with a lesson this time.
你要知道
You need to learn
了解  不等于信任
the difference between knowing someone and trusting them.
看  这小子我信任
See, this kid I can trust.
因为他看重HR吗  不
Because he values HR? No.
因为他害怕我们
It's because he's scared of us.
明白了吗
You got it?
明白了  谢谢教育  老大
Yeah. Thanks for the lesson, boss.
这个还不是教育
That ain't the lesson.
莫洛佐夫那老头儿犯了错
Old man Morozov made the mistake of
我骂他是贼的时候  掏了枪
pulling a gun when I called him out as a thief.
后座上有一把铲子
There's a shovel in the backseat.
六尺之下  小子
6 feet, kid.
美国埋棺材的标准深度
别敷衍
Don't skimp.
■
破译中情局信号
一号牢房通过三道守卫  长官
Cells one through three secure, sir.
希望你脑袋里的声音心里有数
Hope the voice in your head knows what it's doing.
得取下来了
That's gotta go.
日落  渥太华  左  右  左  右  一  二  三
Sundown, Ottawa, left, right, left, right, one, two, three.
你真会甜言蜜语
You say the sweetest things.
迪尔伯恩探员
Agent Dearborn?
我是尼克・布雷肯里奇  主审官
Nick Breckenridge. Chief interrogator.
新"货"现在才到有点迟
Little late to be checking in a new asset.
我们正准备转送所有犯人
We're prepping all prisoners for transport.
转送  我们才刚到
Transport? We just got here.
你知道规定的  迪尔伯恩
You know the drill, Dearborn.
每隔72小时就转移他们
We move these guys every 72 hours.
就能无限期审问了
You get to interrogate indefinitely.
现在  我得确认信息
Now, I need some info.
加密无线电老是出毛病
Encrypted radios always acting up.
-行动名称  -日落
- Name of operation? - Sundown.
-"货"原产地  -渥太华
- Asset's place of origin? - Ottawa.
转送认证号码
Transport authentication number?
交接点的执行警卫应该给你了
Should have gotten it from the operative guarding the pickup site.
那位压力过大
Stress was high on this one.
肯定是忘了
Must have forgot.
你们这群特工自以为能在这里
You NOC types think you can just come in here
横行无忌藐视规章  是吧
and ignore all kinds of protocol, don't you?
没认证号码  没权限
No authentication number, no access.
-有人知道怎么  -左  右
- Does anybody know how to-- - Left, right.
左  右  一  二  三
Left, right, one, two, three.
我们在训练营总是用这个
We use them all the time at the farm.
把这个交给下一交接点的警卫
Give that to the intake guard at the next site.
下一次  记住你该死的认证号码
And next time, remember your damn authentication number.
■
破译中情局信号
还在搜查格林菲尔德的公寓  芬奇
Still searching Greenfield's apartment, Finch.
继续找  里瑟先生
Keep looking, Mr. Reese.
目前你找到的书无一匹配
None of the books you've found so far match the code.
-厨房里没找到  -这里也没有
- The kitchen's clean. - No luck here either.
好吧  肯定就在哪儿藏着呢
All right, it's gotta be somewhere.
寻宝游戏
Scavenger hunt.
什么
What?
我和杰森无聊时常玩的一个游戏
It's a game that Jason and I used to play when we were bored.
我们从对方那里偷件东西
We would steal something from each other.
然后藏在房子里
Then we'd hide it in the house,
杰森总是输
except Jason would always lose
因为他每次都藏在同一个地方
because he always chose the same place.
暖气口
The heating vent.
愿意重温下历史吗  芬奇
Care to brush up on your history, Finch?
《美国革命简史》
The American Revolution - a concise history.
我怎么毫不惊讶呢  我看看
Why am I not surprised? Let me see.
从网上找到一份副本
I've located a copy online.
似乎匹配代码算法
It seems to match the algorithm the code is based on.
-我开始破译  -太好了
- I'll start deciphering. - Great.
斯隆和我会
Sloan and I will--
斯隆呢
Where's Sloan?
抓住他
Grab him!
快点  抓紧时间
Hurry, we're on the clock here.
走
Get out of here!
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
里瑟先生  你还好吗
Mr. Reese, are you all right?
我们走
Let's go.
交火了
Shots fired.
他和那西装男在一起
He's with the guy in the suit.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
科利尔
Collier.
里瑟先生  你还好吗
Mr. Reese, are you all right?
你说得没错  芬奇
You're right, Finch.
是科利尔  斯隆被带走了
It's Collier. Sloan's gone.
我们没办法追踪他
And we have no way to track him.
恐怕事情越来越糟了
I'm afraid it gets worse.
我破译了更多代码  发现了他们的目的
I've deciphered enough of the code to learn its purpose.
他们计划今晚杀掉杰森・格林菲尔德
It's a plan to kill Jason Greenfield tonight.
格林菲尔德
Greenfield?
他不是已经死了吗
Isn't he already dead?
你们不能这么一直转移我
You can't keep moving me like this.
我是美国公民  我享有法定权利
I'm an American! I have rights.
你们连我的名字都不知道了吧
Do you even know my name?
杰森・格林菲尔德  是吧
Jason Greenfield, I presume?
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
我知道你不少事  杰森
I know a lot about you, Jason.
我知道你为一个边缘活动组织黑进政府网络
I know you hacked government sites for a fringe group of activists,
无法忍受那组织转向暴力
got squeamish when the group turned violent,
于是和联邦政府达成协议以获得新身份
cut a deal with the Feds in exchange for a new life,
却被他们摆了一道  沦落至此
and got screwed over by them and stuck in here.
你究竟是谁
Who the hell are you?
回答我
Answer me.
我们有点赶时间
We're on a bit of a clock here,
你这无谓的脾气就免了吧
so let's dispense with the temper tantrum.
回答你的问题  我和你一样
To answer your question, I'm like you.
2009年联调局特洛伊木马  蠕虫病毒
FBI Trojan Horse of 2009, the null worm.
什么 是你
What, that was you?
那玩意一周内就感染了
That thing infected over 7 million computers
全世界超过七百万台电脑
worldwide in less than a week.
如果是你设计了那病毒
If you designed the worm,
那你肯定能说出是如何
then you must be able to tell me how--
自执行附件重写操作系统
A self-executing attachment rewrites the OS
感染附近的蓝牙设备  无线传播
to infect nearby Bluetooth devices and spread wirelessly.
那是很久之前了
That was a long time ago.
我对你更感兴趣  杰森
I'm more interested in you, Jason.
杰森不存在了
Jason doesn't exist anymore.
那些中情局骗子伪造了我的死亡
Those CIA liars faked my death.
这本来是为了保护我
It was supposed to be for my protection.
作为回报  我把那个组织的情况都告诉他们
In return, I give them everything about the group.
没想到  他们把我丢到这个移动黑牢
Instead, they brought me to this mobile black site.
现在  他们可以无限期审问我了
And now, they can question me forever.
向不值得信任的人求助  结果当然不妙
Must have gotten bad for you to reach out to people you don't trust.
那组织杀了人
The group murdered someone...
一名数据掮客
a data broker.
是我的错
And it's my fault.
是我最初对"时刻警惕"说出他的事
I'm the one who told Vigilance about him in the first place.
-时刻警惕  -组织的名字
- Vigilance? - That's their name.
"自由的代价是时刻警惕"
"Eternal vigilance is the price of liberty."
语出美国革命主要领导人之一托马斯・杰斐逊
我说我们应该吓吓那混蛋
I said we should scare the bastard,
科利尔却说服组织  应该更加
but Collier convinced the group that it was time for more...
激进
aggressive action.
我不想杀人
I'm not a killer.
转送车到了
Transport's here.
准备转移
Prepare to move out.
你还没告诉我你怎么会在这儿
So you never told me why you're here.
很简单  杰森
Simple, Jason.
我为你而来
I'm here for you.
我随行
I'll be right along.
绝不能让这位离开我的视线
I'm not letting this one out of my sight.
这么说斯隆死去的兄弟其实还活着
So Sloan's dead brother is really alive?
对  看来杰森・格林菲尔德向中情局自首了
Yes, it seems Jason Greenfield turned himself in to the CIA.
现在  科利尔想杀了这个叛徒
And now, Collier wants to kill him for being a traitor.
没错
Precisely.
6点30  刺杀行动队集合
7点15  卧底备好漆弹在路口就位
7点25  刺杀行动队抵达路口
7点30  开始行动
7点35  撤离路口
按照计划  刺杀格林菲尔德先生的行动
According to the plan, the assassination of Mr. Greenfield
定于一小时内执行
is scheduled to take place within the hour.
他们多半会在执行任务的路上审问斯隆
They're probably going to interrogate Sloan on the way to their mission.
只要查出他们要去哪里杀害格林菲尔德
So if we can find where they're going to kill Greenfield,
我们就还有机会救他们两个
then we still have a chance to save them both.
给我具体位置  芬奇
Just give me a location, Finch.
找到了  下城区一个路口
Got it. An intersection downtown.
我把坐标发给你
I'm sending you the coordinates.
我就去
I'm on my way.
你是他哥哥
So you're his brother.
杰森说他没家人
Jason said he had no family.
为什么现在开始查他
What made you choose to look into him now?
不关你的事
None of your business.
你知道吗
You know what?
你说得对
That is right.
我们"时刻警惕"的成员非常看重隐私
We members of Vigilance value privacy,
虽然政府不
even if the government doesn't.
尽管如此  你查杰森的生活
However, when you started digging into Jason's life,
就查到了我们头上
you also dug into ours,
我们的方略  我们的计划
our methods, our plans,
这对我可是坏消息
which brings me to some rather bad news.
我们投过票
We took a vote
看能不能容你活下去
as to whether we could possibly let you live,
结果恐怕是不如你意
and I'm afraid it didn't go your way.
我现在可以做的不多了
My options at this point are limited,
但是我保证只要你老实交待
but what I can offer you is a quick exchange of words
就让你死个痛快
followed by an even quicker death.
我要知道关于我们的组织你都知道什么
I need to know exactly how much you know about our group
跟谁说过
and who you've told.
先说跟你在一起的那两个人
Let's start with those two men I've seen you with.
他们是谁  联调局  国安局
Who are they? Feds? NSA?
我不知道  好吗
I don't know, okay?
我不知道他们为什么会帮我
I don't know why they're helping me.
我不知道他们为什么关心
I don't know why they care.
我只知道杰森犯了错
All I know is Jason made a mistake
不该跟你们混
falling in with you guys.
他认清之后  想要退出
And when he realized it and he tried to get out,
你们就杀了他
you killed him for it.
你这可搞错了  斯隆先生
Seems you've gotten ahead of things, Mr. Sloan.
杰森・格林菲尔德可活得好好的
Jason Greenfield is very much alive.
你们没杀他
You didn't kill him?
没有
No.
但我们正要去
But we are about to.
你可以近距离亲眼目睹
And you're gonna have a front-row seat.
我们到了
We're here.
情况会有点混乱
Things are about to get a bit hectic.
我们只能迟点再聊了
We'll have to continue this conversation later.
回见  斯隆先生
Until then, Mr. Sloan.
芬奇  我到路口了
Finch, I'm at the intersection.
看到科利尔的车了
And there is Collier's van.
千万小心  里瑟先生
Be careful, Mr. Reese.
你干什么
What are you doing?
十秒
In ten seconds,
准备好
brace yourself.
准备什么
For what?
"撞击"
Impact.
-肖  -现在
- Shaw? - Now.
里瑟先生  怎么回事
Mr. Reese, what's happening?
上上  行动
Go, go! move!
我找到肖了
I just found Shaw.
不幸的是  科利尔也一样
Unfortunately, so did Collier.
? One, two, three, four, five ?
? Break down, baby ?
? Listen to this, just listen to this ?
? Just listen to this, just listen to this ?
听到你的声音真好
So good to hear your voice.
? Just listen to this, just listen to this ?
该走了  杰森
Time to go, Jason.
? The number song, but before I start ?
? Let's have the countdown ?
杰森
Jason?
? Just listen to this, just listen to this ?
-肖  -里瑟
- Shaw. - Reese.
忙着救人
Gotta save somebody.
深有同感
Know the feeling.
我刚才看到个人
I saw somebody out there.
蒂姆・斯隆  知道他为什么在这儿吗
Tim Sloan. Do you know why he's here?
他还好吗
Is he okay?
你有没有看见一个人朝他过去了
Did you see a man heading his way?
高个  高档西装
Tall, nice suit?
看见了
Yeah.
他会没事
He'll be fine.
你的新身份
Your new identity
银行账户密码  里面有两百五十万
and the pass code to a bank account with $2.5 million.
去卡塔赫纳  在大博卡区找"蓝色太阳"酒吧
Go to Cartagena, find a bar called Sol Azul in Boca Grande.
哥伦比亚海港城市
-找鲁伊兹  -他是谁
- Ask for Ruiz. - Who's he?
不知道
I have no idea.
走吧
Now go.
为什么  为什么你要帮我
Why-- why are you helping me?
我只是听命行事
I'm just following orders,
不过我猜  你必不可少
but my guess is you're necessary.
? One, two, three, four, five ?
她在这儿
There she is.
我想软件上帝
I guess a software omniscience
遇着没子弹也束手无策
isn't much help if you're out of bullets.
好了  贱人  格林菲尔德呢
All right, bitch. Where's Greenfield?
你冲我们笑什么
Why are you smiling at us?
我可不是冲你笑
I'm not smiling at you.
我知道你会为我回来
I knew you'd come back for me.
任务完成了吗
Mission accomplished?
当然
Absolutely.
很好
Good.
别再靠近了
That's far enough,
如果你还想保住斯隆先生的命
assuming you'd like Mr. Sloan to survive this encounter.
彼得・科利尔
Peter Collier.
看来你知道我的名字
You seem to know my name,
名字之一
one of 'em,
但我却不认识你
but I can't say the same about you.
我是被你从背后放枪的人
I'm the guy you shot in the back,
现在来讨回这笔了
and I'm here to return the favor.
动手之前
Before you do,
也许你愿意告诉我  为什么
perhaps you'd like to tell me how it is
"时刻警惕"一有行动你就能凭空现身
you manage to keep showing up at Vigilance operations.
我顽强啊
I'm persistent.
能量加顽强可以征服一切
And energy and persistence conquer all things.
本杰明・富兰克林
Benjamin Franklin.
你们很痴迷美国革命  是吧
You guys got a thing for the American Revolution, don't you?
没错
That's true.
事实上  很快就该再来一场了
In fact, it may soon be time for another one.
得了  科利尔  结束了
Forget it, collier. It's over.
你我之间会有一个人结束
But only for one of us.
要么你抓我
You can take me,
要么你救斯隆
or you can save Sloan.
芬奇  科利尔开枪打中了斯隆的股动脉
Finch, Collier shot Sloan in the femoral artery.
我们需要帮助
We need help.
派救护车过去了  里瑟先生
There's an ambulance on the way, Mr. Reese.
坚持住  你会没事的
Hang in there. You're gonna be all right.
受到教育了吗  拉斯基
You learn your lesson, Laskey?
六尺之下  我没敷衍
6 feet. I didn't skimp.
昨晚还好吗  拉斯基
How was your night, Laskey?
睡得好吗
Sleep good?
我的名字是米哈伊尔・拉斯里奇
My name is Mikhail Lesnichy.
警队中有我们十二名俄罗斯人
There are 12 of us Russians on the force.
HR把能确保忠心的人安排进了纽约警队
So HR is seeding the NYPD with cops they know will be loyal
以此巩固他们和俄罗斯黑帮之间的交易
and cementing their deal with the Russian mob in the process.
你从莫洛佐夫那里收的钱呢
What about that money you got from Morozov?
HR贮存了起来
HR's stockpiling it.
不知道要干什么  反正  他们手头有数百万
I don't know what for, but whatever it is, they have millions.
事态会发展得比昨晚还糟糕
It gets worse than last night, you know.
会有什么比埋葬朋友更糟糕
What's worse than burying a friend?
很高兴看到你出院  斯隆先生
Good to see you out of the hospital, Mr. Sloan.
你气色不错
You're looking well.
我对你们真是感激不尽
I can't thank you guys enough,
不只是救了我
not just for saving me
还帮我找到了我弟弟
but for helping me find my brother,
尽管只是短短一瞬
even if it was for a second.
你也帮了我们很多
you helped us as much as we helped you.
正是  你证明了自己是个优秀的侦探
Indeed, you've proven yourself to be quite a fine detective,
如雷蒙德・钱德勒笔下一般
one worthy of Raymond Chandler.
他们在整理杰森的东西  准备今天拍卖
They're packing up Jason's stuff for auction today,
所以我就想顺路过来
so I figure I'd stop in
最后看一眼
and take one last look around.
找件纪念品吗
Maybe find a remembrance?
已经有了
Already have one.
很适合你
It suits you.
祝你好运  斯隆先生
Good luck, Mr. Sloan.
抱歉
Excuse me.
-喂  -蒂姆  蒂姆・斯隆
- Hello? - Tim? Tim Sloan?
杰森  你在哪里
Jason? Where are you?
我说了你都不会相信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
我想办法开了一条安全线路
Listen, I've managed to create a secure stream,
让我们能说上话  但是只能维持约三十秒
so we can talk, but it'll only last 30 seconds or so, and...
我只想跟你说  谢谢
I just wanted to tell you thanks.
我跟那些人混在一起  以为有了新家
Those guys I got involved with, I thought I'd found a new family,
但我早该知道  你才是我的家人
but I should've known. You're my family.
杰森
Jason,
我想你知道
I want you to know
我拿了你的一些东西
that I have something of yours,
我会保管好  等着下次见面
and I'm gonna hold on to it until next time.
听起来不错  蒂姆
That sounds good, Tim.
你永远是我哥哥
You'll always be my brother.
我们得留意他
We're gonna have to keep an eye on him.
科利尔也许会卷土重来
Collier may try again.
既然"时刻警惕"想要场革命
If Vigilance wants a revolution,
这恐怕只是第一枪
these may only be the opening shots.
同样令人忧心的是  机器居然
Equally troubling, the machine appears to
派了两个队往同一战场执行不同任务
have sent two teams into the same battle with different goals.
为什么对我们隐瞒根和肖的事
Why keep us in the dark about Root and Shaw?
说到这个
Speaking of which,
你有没有想好要怎么处理根
have you figured out what to do with Root yet?
你喜欢的话  这里有更舒服点的椅子
There are more comfortable chairs, if you'd rather...
还有把沙发椅
Not to mention a padded bench,
拼起来就是张很舒服的床
which doubles as quite a comfortable bed,
虽然略小点
albeit a small one.
而且全都位于
And all within the proximity radius
我可爱的新脚环容许的范围内
programmed into my lovely new ankle accessory.
我试过了  只要一出范围  结果惨痛
I found out the hard way what happens if I cross it.
只想确保你该有的都有
Just making sure you have everything you need.
这里可供阅读的倒是不缺
There's no shortage of reading material.
这点确保了  哈罗德
That's for sure, Harold.
正好占住脑子
Keeps the mind occupied.
你非常清楚应该由谁来占住我的脑子
You know damn well who's supposed to be occupying my mind.
恐怕那没得商量
I'm afraid that's out of the question.
想来即使我弄到了无线设备
I suppose that even if I managed to get access to a wireless device,
你在这里设的静电屏蔽罩
the Faraday Cage you've constructed in here
也会让我无法联络她
would prevent me from communicating with her.
你的推理能力向来无懈可击
Your powers of deduction are as ever impeccable.
而你对人称代词的选择  颇具启发性
And your choice of pronoun-- illuminating.
如果没别的事
If there's nothing else...
你关押我违抗了机器的意志  哈罗德
You're going against the machine's wishes by keeping me here, Harold.
你只会激怒她
You're only gonna make her angry.
你能想象
Can you imagine
她被激怒后会是何等的威力吗
what a being that powerful will do when she's angry?
你怎么就能确定  格罗夫斯女士
How can you be so certain, Ms. Groves,
机器不希望你乖乖待在这里呢
that the machine does not wish you to be precisely where you are?